(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T20:09:09.083685",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
焼けるような陽射し
With the scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
sequins floating on the water,
饒ぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
behind playful summer colors and backlight,
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
I'm recalling the youth of that day.
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up the cuffs of my denim,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
running barefoot on the sandy beach.
硝子の縁で回り回る 輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
Spinning along the glass edge, a shining lapis lazuli marble—
なんか、その笑顔と紙一重だ
somehow, it's a hair's breadth from that smile.
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peeking through the film, it's non-fiction;
彩りに剥いだされたメモリー
a memory stripped of its colors.
リセットなんて出来ないから
Since you can't just reset it,
love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー アルゴリズムの中 (Ooh)
Dance in the midsummer, inside the algorithm (Ooh).
瞬息でダビングして 切り取ってきっと愛だ
Dubbing in an instant, cutting it out—surely this is love!
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
Surely this is love (Ooh).
二度と忘れないように (Oh)
So I'll never forget it (Oh)...
Le Lemon Lime Orange キミと一生分の想い出
Le Lemon Lime Orange, memories for a lifetime with you.
(Oh)
何気ない一日が One of a kind
An ordinary day is one of a kind.
焼けるような陽射し
With the scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
sequins floating on the water,
饒ぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
behind playful summer colors and backlight,
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
I'm recalling the youth of that day.
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up the cuffs of my denim,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
running barefoot on the sandy beach.
硝子の縁で回り回る 輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
Spinning along the glass edge, a shining lapis lazuli marble—
なんか、その笑顔と紙一重だ
somehow, it's a hair's breadth from that smile.
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peeking through the film, it's non-fiction;
彩りに剥いだされたメモリー
a memory stripped of its colors.
リセットなんて出来ないから
Since you can't just reset it,
Love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー アルゴリズムの中 (Ooh)
Dance in the midsummer, inside the algorithm (Ooh).
瞬息でダビングして 切り取ってきっと愛だ
Dubbing in an instant, cutting it out—surely this is love!
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
Surely this is love (Ooh).
二度と忘れないように (Oh)
So I'll never forget it (Oh)...
Le Lemon Lime Orange キミと一生分の想い出
Le Lemon Lime Orange, memories for a lifetime with you.
(Oh)
何気ない一日が One of a kind
An ordinary day is one of a kind.
氷が溶けては渦巻いた
Ice melting and swirling around,
魔法の杖がわりのマドラー
a muddler acting as a magic wand.
喉の奥くすぐる炭酸
Carbonation tickling the back of my throat,
香る柑橘系のフレーバー
a fragrant citrus-flavored wave
爽やかな気流にのって 波の還りを見守ってる Beachside
riding on a fresh breeze, watching over the returning waves at the beachside.
あどけない面影に焦がれ
Yearning for innocent silhouettes,
僅かに触れそうな指先
fingertips that almost seem to touch.
煌めきで上塗りしてしまうわ
I'll just paint it over with radiance!
Get ahead of what you used to be
踊ってミッドサマー アルゴリズムの中 (Ooh)
Dance in the midsummer, inside the algorithm (Ooh).
瞬息でダビングして 切り取ってきっと愛だ
Dubbing in an instant, cutting it out—surely this is love!
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
Surely this is love (Ooh).
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it...
ミッドサマーシトラス Oh yeah いつだって We got love!! Okay
Midsummer Citrus, oh yeah, we always got love!! Okay.
キミといるだけで Feel so nice ココロはまた実り
Just being with you feels so nice, my heart bears fruit once again.
寝起きの太陽も 願ってもない燦々日和？
Even the morning sun—could this be the brightest weather we could ask for?
白飛びしてしまうほど 眩いのは夏のせい
So blinding it washes everything out—it must be summer's fault.
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance in the midsummer...
灼き付くような陽射し
Scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
sparkling sequins on the water's surface.
揺蕩う夏色と逆光の裏側で あの日の青春を呼び起こしている
Amidst flickering summer hues and backlight, calling back youth.
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up my denim cuffs,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
running barefoot on the sand.
硝子の淵で回り回る
Spinning round on the edge of glass,
輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
a shining azure glass marble.
なんだか、その笑顔と紙一重だ (Ooh)
Somehow inseparable from that smile... (Ooh)
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peeking through the film, non-fiction,
彩りに縛られたメモリー
memories bound by vivid colors.
リセットなんて出来ないから
You can't just reset it, so
love yourself just as you are now (Oh)
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance, Midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中 (Ooh)
in the algorithm... (Ooh)
瞬息でダビングして
dubbing in a split second,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
capturing all emotions.
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
This surely is love... (Ooh)
二度と忘れないように (Oh)
So we'll never forget it. (Oh)
Le Lemon Lime Orange
キミと一生分の想い出 (Oh)
memories with you for a lifetime. (Oh)
何気ない一日が one of a kind
Every ordinary day is one of a kind.
はい、お疲れ様でしたー！
Yes, great work everyone!
せーの、リッツ・トプ！
Ready, set, Rits Top!
We are ReGLOSS! ReGLOSS!
さあ、それでは自己紹介いこう！
Now then, let's do self-introductions!
プリズムスターのハレレブデバイス一日作り続けたら目がかすんで画面見えなくてこんにちは！
Making Prism Star's HareReubu device all day, my eyes got blurry! Hello!
カリポジティブ、ジニアス！
Kari-positive, genius!
ホロライブデバイスReGLOSSの一条莉々華だよ！イエーイ！
I'm Ichijou Ririka of Hololive Device ReGLOSS! Yay!
エアブンブンブー！ホロライブデバイスカリビアンスタリゴ一丁パンチョ！おっとき初めれー！
Air boom boom boom! Caribbean Starily Go one chopper! Let it begin!
ホロライブデバイスReGLOSSの人間投資家ねだくんと！
Hololive Device ReGLOSS human investor Neda-kun and...
十五時ーわ、全然見えない！十五時ーら、んでございます！イエーイ！
3 PM—wait, can't see at all! 3 PM—ra, here we are! Yay!
いきなりですがなんと新曲を初披露させていただきました！イエーイ！
Suddenly, we debuted our new song! Yay!
みんなどうだったー？楽しかったー？
How was it, everyone? Did you enjoy it?
最初さー、本当にごめんなさい！本当にごめんなさい！
At first, I'm so sorry! I'm really sorry!
本当にごめんなさい！本当に、お姉さん、ごめんなさい！
I'm really sorry! Really, big sister, I'm sorry!
最初ね、あの、これぜひアーカイブで確認してほしいんですけども
At first, please definitely check the archive for this, but
あの、我々が、あの、足でじゃんけんをするっていう
um, we were supposed to play rock-paper-scissors with our feet—
そう、あの、あっち向いてホイをするシーンがあるんだよね。そう。
right, there's a scene where we do "look that way." Right.
で、そこで、あの事前の打ち合わせと、あの、違うものが出てしまって (笑)
And then, something different from our prior meeting came out (laughs).
なのに、なんか、あの、あっち向いてホイするっていう
Even though we were supposed to do "look that way"—
しかも1回も、あの、あっち向いてホイ成功しなかったんだけど、なんか、なんか、リリカが勝ったことになってて (笑)
And we didn't succeed once, but somehow it ended up with Ririka winning (laughs).
もっそ、もう、みんな、リリカも笑ったりさ、みんな笑ってるし
Everyone, Ririka was laughing too, and everyone was laughing,
でもソロのパート頑張らなきゃって、元より声めっちゃ震えてた。
but thinking we had to do our solo parts right, our voices shook.
え、待って、話題の声聞こえちゃってたのかな？ (聞こえてたよ)
Wait, could our chat voices be heard? (They could be heard)
コメント欄見えて、笑っとるやんってなって (笑)
Seeing the comment section made us think, "We're laughing!" (laughs)
そう、実はね、そんなこんながあったんですけれど、まあ、そんな、こんなもね、まあ、生配信、ライブの醍醐味でございます。
Right, actually, things like that happened, but that's the charm of a live stream.
そうですね、初めから。まあ、1回目だからバレてないやろ。
That's right. From the start. Well, since it's the first time, it wasn't noticed.
ああいうのって言われてるかもしれない。バレるバレる。
They might say that. It's totally noticeable.
はい、ということでね、こんなミッドサマーストラスなんですが、なんと、もうすでにね、MVが公開されております！
Yes, so that's Midsummer Citrus, but the MV has already been released!
イエーイ！みんな見てくれたかな？
Yay! Did everyone watch it?
せっかくなんだからね、1曲ずつ加速していけますか？じゃあここからでパンチョ。
Since we have the chance, can we speed up song by song? Let's start from here.
え、なんか、やっぱさ、ナッ臭って言ったらこう、ハッピー、ハッピーって感じなのかなって思うと、ちょっとこうノスタルジックな？ちょっとエモい感じの過去を彷彿とさせる、いいナッ臭の思い出、みたいな感じでエモい、いい曲だなあって思ってました。
When you say summer-ish, you'd think happy-happy, but it's nostalgic and emotional—a wonderful song.
いいね！こういうのいいじゃん、歌ではね。
That's nice! This is great, especially in song.
え、歌では、やっぱりこう制服着てたりしてたから、学生時代のことをやっぱ思い出したりしたし、
In the song, since we wore uniforms, it made me recall my student days,
あと、すごい爽やかな夏曲だったから、外に出てね、暑い夏の時に出て聞きながら道を歩いてたら涼しくなるのかなと思いました！いっぱい聴いてください！
and since it was a refreshing summer song, walking outside in the hot summer while listening might feel cooler! Please listen!
みんな聴いてねー！
Everyone, listen to it!
そして、リリカはね、なんかMVにやっぱり私たちのカット、青空も含めてね、あのリリカのカットがたくさん入ってて、なんかそれを見てるだけでちょっとニヤニヤしちゃった。
And in the MV, there were lots of cuts of us including the blue sky, and just watching Ririka's cuts made me grin.
真夏のなのに！
Even though it's midsummer!
なのに、すごいリリカが映ってる所を隣で、ねえ、水面見ながらニヤニヤしてたの。
Even so, right next to her while seeing Ririka on screen, she was grinning looking at the water.
でもうまくやってるそれは。
But you're handling that well.
よくやってる。でもね、リリカのこと頑なにしてるから、ああ、再現されてるそうなんです。なので、いろいろね、ちょっと細かいところをぜひみんなも見てみてください。
Doing well. But since she's stubborn about Ririka, it's reproduced. Please check out all the fine details.
そして、あの、このね、え、サビの冒頭、踊ってミッドサマってある通り、こういうところとかね、
And at the start of the chorus, as it says "Dance, Midsummer," places like this too—
すごくノりやすくて踊りやすい曲なんじゃないかなと思いますんで、ぜひ皆さんも踊って、ミッドサマやってください！やってねー！
I think it's a song that's easy to dance to, so please everyone dance and do Midsummer! Do it!
え、ということで今回ね、え、MVに関わってくださった監督、え、クリエイターの皆様、素敵に撮影してくださって本当にありがとうございました！
So this time, the directors and creators involved in the MV, thank you so much for shooting it wonderfully!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
え、そして、え、ついに
And, finally—
ついに！明日0時、え、つまり今日の24時に
Finally! Tomorrow at 0:00, meaning today at 24:00,
こちらね、え、ミッドサマーストラスデジタルリリースしちゃいます！イエーイ！
we are digitally releasing Midsummer Citrus! Yay!
やったー！
Yay!
だから日付が変わったタイミングですね、え、リグロスといえばおなじみの
That's the timing when the date changes, speaking of ReGLOSS...
大弌らさん、前島総師さんに手掛けていただいた
Produced by Ootora-san and Maeshima Soushi-san,
爽やかなメロディと心地よいリズムが、夏の暑さを吹き飛ばしてくれるような一曲でございます。
this refreshing melody and pleasant rhythm will blow away the summer heat.
ぜひこの夏はミッドサマーシトラスを聴いて、ReGLOSSとの夏の思い出をたくさん作りましょう！
Be sure to listen to "Midsummer Citrus" this summer and make lots of summer memories with ReGLOSS!
ということで、今日はね、ここから、まあ別のまた夏歌を歌っていこうと思うんですけれど
So today, we're going to sing another summer song from here,
事前にね、あのアンケートでみんなにね、応募してもらったのも歌いますので、楽しみにしといてください！
and we'll also be singing the ones you voted for in the survey beforehand, so look forward to it!
じゃあ、ちょっとね、夏のビーチということで、あまりにも暑くて倒れてしまいそうなので移動しますか！
Well, since it's a summer beach, it's way too hot and we might collapse, so shall we move?
移動しました！
We moved!
てか何々？暑い暑い暑い！
Wait, what's this? Hot, hot, hot!
あ、そうだ、そうだ。
Ah, that's right.
暑い暑い暑い暑い！
Hot, hot, hot, hot!
じゃあ行きますか、ね？どこ行こうかネ？
Shall we go? Where should we go?
やっちまった！
I messed up!
じゃあカラオケ向かいますか？カラオケ行こ行こ！
Shall we head to karaoke? Let's go to karaoke!
歌うんだからね。歌うならやっぱり...
We're going to sing, after all. If we sing, then as expected...
予約持ってる？予約持ってるよ！
Do you have a reservation? I have one!
あ、アプリダウンロードしてないかも。
Ah, I might not have downloaded the app.
あ、でもカードで持ってるから大丈夫。
Ah, I have it on a card, so it's fine.
え、予約したじゃん。
Eh, you reserved it, right?
しょぼいな。
Lame.
え、何夏歌歌おうかな？え、悩むね。
Eh, what summer song should I sing? I'm torn.
でもさ、リクエストをね、いただいておりますからね。
But you know, we've received requests, so...
ありがたい！みんなのリクエストしたからありがちょね。もしかしたら...
Thank God! Thank you for everyone's requests. If it turns out...
え、ミッドサマーシトラス？歌ってる場合じゃないのよ。
Eh, "Midsummer Citrus"? This isn't the time to be singing that.
また、じゃ、ジャンケンのやり直しから！
Let's start over with rock-paper-scissors!
最初はグー、じゃんけんぽん！あいこでしょ！
Rock, paper, scissors, go! Aiko de sho!
え、すごいポスターあるじゃん！
Eh, there's an amazing poster!
あ、ポスター！
Ah, poster!
急にパスタ出てきた。
Pasta suddenly appeared.
カラオケすごいね！
Karaoke is amazing!
え、じゃあ、コーンスープ。
Eh, then, corn soup.
え、じゃあ私ね、コーンスープと、あとカルピス二個欲しい。
Eh, then I want corn soup and two Calpis.
え、じゃあ私ウーロン茶！
Eh, then I'll have oolong tea!
あ、じゃあ、あの全部に上にソフトクリームつけて。
Ah, then put soft serve ice cream on top of all of them.
はい、じゃあ時間もないので、早速歌っていこうと思います！
Okay, since we don't have much time, let's start singing right away!
いやー何の歌歌うのかな、楽しみだね。
I wonder what song we'll sing, I'm looking forward to it.
一番最初に歌いたい人、誰ですか？
Who wants to sing first?
はい！
Me!
え、かなでちゃん！
Eh, Kanade-chan!
行くじゃん！
Let's go!
あのミッドサマーシトラスね、あんだけ歌って踊った後に...
After singing and dancing so much to "Midsummer Citrus"...
一発目この元気さでいける人、なかなかないよ。
There's hardly anyone who can go with this much energy on the first try.
かなでちゃん、番号は？
Kanade-chan, what's the number?
番号ね、夏中盛り上げていこうじゃん！
The number is... let's liven up the whole summer!
じゃあその番号からいきましょう！お願いします！
Well, let's go with that number! Please!
「サンオイル 背中に塗って！」と
"Put sunscreen on my back!"
水着の上 外しながら寝そべった
You said while lying down and taking off your swimsuit top.
大胆な君の一言は
That bold remark of yours
甘ったるい 匂いがした
Had a sweet scent.
どこまでも青い海と空
The endless blue sea and sky
僕たちの関係に似てる
Are like our relationship.
水平線は 交わってるのに
Even though the horizon crosses
そう 今はまだ わがままな妹のようさ
Yes, you're still like a spoiled younger sister.
真夏の Sounds good! つぶやきながら
Midsummer Sounds good! While murmuring
次のステップへ 進みたいね 恋のカリキュラム
I want to advance to the next step, a love curriculum.
波音 Sounds good! 心が騒ぐよ
The sound of the waves Sounds good! My heart is pounding.
去年よりも 僕は本気になる
I'm more serious than last year.
砂浜で肌を焼いている
Burning my skin on the beach
君を置いて 僕は一人泳いだよ
I left you and swam alone.
僕は一人泳いだよ
I left you and went swimming alone.
その後のいきなりのキスは
The sudden kiss after that
塩辛い味がした
had a salty taste.
さっきまでのあの風景とは
Compared to that scenery from just a moment ago,
空気まで変わった気がする
I feel like even the air has changed.
海と空がちゃんと向き合って
The sea and the sky are facing each other properly,
そうお互いのその青さ映し合っている
yeah, reflecting each other's blue.
渚のGood job!
Nagisa no Good job!
愛しい人よ
My beloved,
ずっと切なくて言えなかった 君が近すぎて
I was too close to say how much I cared.
きっかけGood job! 素直になるんだ
Kikkake Good job! I'll be honest.
手を伸ばそう
Let's reach out our hands,
恋の季節じゃないか!
isn't it the season of love?
真夏のSounds good! つぶやきながら
Manatsu no Sounds good! While whispering,
次のステップへ進みたいね 恋のカリキュラム
I want to advance to the next step, a curriculum of love.
波音Sounds good! 心が騒ぐよ
Namioto Sounds good! My heart is pounding.
去年よりも 僕は本気になる
I'm more serious than I was last year.
真夏のSounds good! 君が好きだ
Manatsu no Sounds good! I love you.
波音Sounds good! やっと言えたよ
Namioto Sounds good! I finally said it.
渚のGood job! 君が好きだ
Nagisa no Good job! I love you.
きっかけGood job! いいタイミングだね
Kikkake Good job! Good timing, huh?
真夏のSounds good!
Manatsu no Sounds good!
いい曲目からぶち上がっていく
Starting strong with a great song!
なんか、アイマミとBももらっているらしいか
It looks like we got some nice vibes and beats too.
ちょっとね、おっさんを入れたい
I kind of want to add some uncle energy.
おっさん入れたい
Add uncle energy!
ちょっと、おっさんモードにする?
Should we switch to uncle mode?
ちょっとおっさんを入れたい
I want to add a bit of uncle energy.
おっさんを入れたい!
Bring on the uncle energy!
ちょっとキラキラしすぎちゃってて
It's getting a bit too sparkly,
おっさんを入れときますね
so I'll add some uncle vibe.
ちなみに何でさ、この曲にしたの?
By the way, why did you choose this song?
え、なんかアンケートにあって、歌えずでチェックを入れた
Well, it was in the survey, so I checked it on Utazu.
なんかもうちょいあるでしょ、こういうところが最高なの
There's got to be more reasons! Parts like this are the best.
でもすごいじゃん、なんかこう白いフナハマ、青いシラ、白いビキニの美少女たちが、キャーってやってる、姿が、こう浮かび上がるのがすごく素敵じゃないですか
Imagining beautiful girls in white bikinis against the blue sky is just wonderful!
なるほどね
I see.
楽しかった、夏曲じゃん
It was fun, what a great summer song.
しかも盛り上がるね、なんか、初めて聴いたんだけど
Even though it's my first time hearing it,
すごい、もうノリノリだった、今
you were totally rocking out just now.
夏って感じだ
It really feels like summer.
ダンスも準備してきたの?
Did you prepare the dance too?
いや、ノリやり
Nah, just went with the flow.
あ、マジで?
Oh, really?
本家のダンスと別にあって、それはちょっとごめんなさい、覚えてきてないですけど
There's an original choreography, but sorry, I didn't memorize it.
でも、即興でやったってことだよね、今ここで
But that means you did it all on the spot right here?
ノリで
Just on a whim.
すごくない?
Isn't that amazing?
いやー、やばちゃ、ありがちょ
Man, that's insane, thanks a lot.
もうプロだったよ、今ね
You looked like a total pro just now.
ウェーブとかやばかった
That wave move was incredible.
すごかった
It was amazing!
じゃ、次の曲に拍手を
Let's give a round of applause for the next song.
ありがちょ
Thanks a lot!
素晴らしい
Wonderful.
次、じゃあ次どうする?
Now, what should we do next?
え、この後歌いたい人いるわけないじゃん
Wait, as if anyone else wants to sing after that!
なんて
Just kidding!
でも一応ダイホだとなでになってる
But according to the lineup, it's set to Nana.
え?
Huh?
えらいよ、すごーい
Good job, that's amazing!
うまーい
So good!
頑張り
Do your best!
からで準備大丈夫?
Are you ready with the karaoke setup?
はい、じゃあ行こ
Yep, let's go!
うん
Yeah.
本能が狂い始める 追い詰められたハツカネズミ
Instincts start to go crazy, like a cornered mouse.
今、絶望の淵に立って 踏切へと飛び出した
Standing in an abyss of despair, I jumped into the railway crossing.
そう君は友達 僕の手を掴めよ
Yes, you're my friend, so take my hand.
そう君は独りさ 居場所なんて無いだろ
Yes, you're all alone, you've got nowhere to belong.
そう 君は独りさ 居場所なんて無いだろ
Yes, you're alone, you've got nowhere to go, do you?
二人きりこの儘 愛し合えるさー。
With just the two of us remaining, we're able to love each other.
繰り返す
It repeats again—
フラッシュバック・蝉の声・ 二度とは帰らぬ君
A flashback of cicadas, and you who will never return.
永遠に千切れてく お揃いのキーホルダー
Our matching keychains are torn apart for all eternity.
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に
The summer has vanished, leaving a girl with pale skin...
哀しい程 取り憑かれて仕舞いたい
so painfully obsessed, I want to be possessed by her.
本性が暴れ始める 九月のスタート 告げるチャイム
My instincts begin to rage as the September chime announces the start.
次の標的に置かれた花瓶 仕掛けたのは僕だった
The vase placed at the next target—it was me who set it up.
そう 君が悪いんだよ 僕だけを見ててよ
That's right, you're in the wrong, so only look at me.
そう 君の苦しみ 助けが欲しいだろ
So your suffering, you want help, don't you?
溺れてく其の手にとそっと口吻をしたー。
Into those drowning hands, I softly kissed.
薄笑いの獣たち その心晴れるまで 爪を突き立てる
The smiling beasts bare their claws until their hearts find peace,
不揃いのスカート 夏の静寂を切り裂くような悲鳴が こだまする教室の窓には青空
with a mismatched skirt, a scream cutting through the summer silence into the blue sky outside the classroom window.
そう 君は友達 僕の手を掴めよ
Yes, you're my friend, take my hand.
そう 君が居なくちゃ 居場所なんて無いんだよ 透き通った世界で愛し合えたらー。
Yes, if you're not here, you have nowhere to belong in this transparent world, and we could love each other.
繰り返す フラッシュバック・蝉の声・ 二度とは帰らぬ君
It repeats again—a flashback of cicadas, and you who will never return.
永遠に千切れてく お揃いのキーホルダー
Our matching keychains are torn apart for all eternity.
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に
The summer has vanished, leaving a girl with pale skin...
哀しい程 取り憑かれて仕舞いたい 透明な君は 僕を指差してたー。
so painfully obsessed, I want to be possessed by her. The transparent you was pointing at me.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い放つ
Releasing a blue dream,
花燃えゆく
The flowers burn away.
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い放つ
Releasing a blue dream,
花燃えゆく
The flowers burn away.
静寂に 落ちる空
The sky falls into silence,
ふたひらの 夢花火
Two petals of dream fireworks.
彼方に 旅立つ
Departing to the distance,
あなたも 見えたの?
Could you also see it?
同じ 光が
The same light...
離れても いつのか日か
Even if we're apart, I believe
出逢えると 信じてる
We will meet again someday.
胸裂く想いを
My heart's bursting feelings...
あなたに 歌うわ
I sing to you.
声が 聴こえる?
Can you hear my voice?
せつなにしひらく それはHANABI
Opening painfully, that is HANABI.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い放つ
Releasing a blue dream,
咲き誇れ 遥か高く
Bloom far and high,
守りゆく その想い
Protecting that feeling,
ひたすら 鳴り響け
Resound purely,
果てるまで せめて強く
At least be strong until the end,
此の花 燃えゆく
This flower burns away.
いくつもの 言の葉を
Countless words of leaves
悪戯に 散らした
Scattered carelessly,
断ちゆく 迷いは
The parting hesitations
静かに 消えたの 明日が見えてる?
Quietly disappeared, can you see tomorrow?
せつなにしひらく それはHANABI
Opening painfully, that is HANABI.
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying,
つかみゆく 幻の花
The flower of a dream to grasp
あたしの手を 零れ落ちて
Spills from my hand.
願うまま この想い あなたに 鳴り渡れ
I wish for this feeling to reach you.
果てるなら せめて強く
If it ends, at least be strong.
此の花 燃えゆく
This flower burns away.
せつなにしひらく それはHANABI
Opening painfully, that is HANABI.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い上がれ
Releasing a blue dream, rise high.
いつの日か めぐり逢えて
We'll meet by chance someday.
繋ぎゆく この想い
This feeling connecting us,
愛しき 君我 いつまでも双片 強く
Beloved you and me, forever strong.
煌いて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い放つ
Releasing a blue dream,
咲き誇れ 遥か高く
Bloom far and high,
守りゆく その想い
Protecting that feeling,
ひたすら 鳴り響け
Resound purely,
果てるまで せめて強く
At least be strong until the end,
此の花 燃えゆく
This flower burns away.
でも、てことは次はラデェンちゃんの番？
So, does that mean next is Raden-chan's turn?
あ、違った違った。番長？君だ！
Ah, wait, no. Bancho? It's you!
番長じゃあ、ちょっと
Bancho, well, um,
ここでまた盛り上がる系の曲を…
here, I'd like to do another hyping song...
おこうかなと、はい。
let's see, yeah.
じゃあ、ちゃっとらの皆さん、エンジョイの準備をお願いしまーす！
So, Chatra everyone, please get ready to enjoy!
エンジョイ！それでは行きましょう、準備OKです！
Enjoy! Now let's go, is everyone ready?
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続け
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, the heartbeat I want to reach you
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
Heart-dancing encore heats up, Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し 音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Surpassing the goal-in, keep swimming riding on the beat
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing
のっきな的な言葉が出てきた ここは心躍るところだから
Fancy words came out, because this is a place where hearts dance
置いてかないよ 追い付けたいなら Get Up Stand Up 行くしかねぇ
I won't leave you behind, if you want to catch up, Get Up Stand Up, you gotta go!
つかえねえやっぱ 気付いたんだ 100% 幸せの意思表示 鳴らせ CLAP CLAP
Useless, huh? I realized it, 100% expression of happiness, ring out CLAP CLAP
仲間同士 夜通し 詰め込んだ アッパーなテンションのシチュエーション
Friends packed together all night in an upper-tension situation
Have a dreamin' グリーディング この場の空気 中心 サークル 繋がるブギー
Have a dreamin' greeting, center of the atmosphere, circle connecting boogie
フリーキー きばらず ここのみんと その価値あるから Swing swing sing a song
Freaky, without straining, everyone here, because it has value, Swing swing sing a song
生真面目 恥ずかしがりでもできる イマジネーション 望むところだ
Even serious and shy people can do it, imagination is what we hope for
茶の間 床の間 ところ構わず ボタンひとつで踊る心が
Regardless of living room or bedroom, with just a button, the heart dances
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続け
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, the heartbeat I want to reach you
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
Heart-dancing encore heats up, Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し 音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Surpassing the goal-in, keep swimming riding on the beat
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing
やっぱりな Hurry up 俺は急いで歯を磨く
As expected, Hurry up, I'm brushing my teeth in a rush
手間は取らせんさぁ見な あみ出すっつか 勝手心騒ぎ出す 時間場所など限らず
I won't take your time, look, spinning out, my heart starts pounding on its own, regardless of time and place
グータラ てきばき 日常 メリハリ 毎日 変わる音 フレッシュ デリバリー
Slacking, efficient, daily contrast, everyday changing sounds, fresh delivery
揺らす Body Rock 増々 ベクトル向かう 矛先はプラスへ
Rocking Body Rock more and more, vector pointing towards the plus side
その長と短 そこがどうかなる 所々 ココロゴト 転がりあう
Long and short, wherever it goes, rolling together here and there
だから今日は 今日 振り切る昨日 心から踊らすこの一時
So today, shake off yesterday, this moment that dances from the bottom of the heart
一度 Go ドア開けたらフロア 浮き足立つ 抜け出す 揺れる Core
Once you open the Go door, the floor gets jittery, breaking out, swaying Core
Up and down こっち タンタ Tap Let's Dance Come on
Up and down this way, Tanta Tap Let's Dance Come on
加速 構うんもんかもう いてもたっても いらんない 心だけじゃ収まんぜ
Accelerate, who cares anymore, can't sit still, doesn't stop with just the heart
Day and Night Shake a body ぎこちないならないで 可愛い 心感じるままに
Day and Night Shake a body, don't be awkward, just as cute as your heart feels
La La La Live Life Good to be Alive 笑い愛し合いされ 喜怒哀楽 刻む
La La La Live Life Good to be Alive, laughing and being loved, engraving emotions
音と言葉 つなぐこの場 届いてるなら Make some noise
This place connecting sound and words, if it reaches you, Make some noise
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続け
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, the heartbeat I want to reach you
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
Heart-dancing encore heats up, Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し 音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Surpassing the goal-in, keep swimming riding on the beat
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing
グレートフル 絵描く スケールはでかく 楽しいもんだ エラく デラックス
Painting a grateful picture, scale is huge, fun things are grand and deluxe
狙う暇なんか単純に簡単 楽しいもんだ エラく デラックス 預けて カウントダウン 3・2・1
No time to aim, simply easy, fun things are grand and deluxe, leave it to countdown 3, 2, 1
なりふり構わず 夢中で駆け抜けろ 息まいて It's like this
Without caring about appearance, run through immersed, breathing It's like this
さらに深い感動へ モーレツ Oh yes ココロオドル 今日へ
To even deeper emotion, fiercely Oh yes, to today where hearts dance
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し 音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Surpassing the goal-in, keep swimming riding on the beat
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続け
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, the heartbeat I want to reach you
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
Heart-dancing encore heats up, Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し 音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Surpassing the goal-in, keep swimming riding on the beat
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing
ココロオドル アンコール わかす Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
Heart-dancing encore heats up, Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今ゴーイング ゴールインより飛び越し 音に乗り泳ぎ続ける
Surpassing the goal-in, keep swimming riding on the beat
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing
ラデレッツゴー！
Let's get it, let's go!
ココロオドルっちゃわ。
That was 'Kokoro Odoru'.
うん、楽しい曲だ。
Yeah, such a fun song.
一人で歌う曲ではない。
Not really a song to sing all by yourself.
それは本当にそう。でもすごいね。
That's so true. But it's amazing.
もう歌いきったよ。すごいエネルギー感じたもいまっ。
Sang it all the way through. Felt so much energy just now.
今日も歌えない？
Can't you sing today anymore?
いやまだ、1周目だからまだまだ。
No way, it's only the first round, still a long way to go.
これで、まだ1周しかしてないですけれど。
Even though we've only done one round so far.
うーん、じゃあどうする？
Hmm, so what should we do?
次、誰歌う？
Next, who's singing?
短い曲調に歌うか！
Shall we sing a short-style song!
長調！長調！
Major key! Major key!
なんだろ？
What is it?
いいよ、じゃあ番長のセンスに任せるわ。
Okay, then I'll leave it to Banchou's taste.
私のセンスで？
With my taste?
オッケーオッケー。準備オッケー？
Okay, okay. Are you ready?
うん、はい！
Yeah, ready!
お願いしまーす！
Let's go!
イケナイ太陽
Forbidden Sun
チョットでいいから 見せてくれないか
Just for a bit, won't you show me?
お前のセクシー・フェロモンで オレ メロメロ
With your sexy pheromones, I'm completely hooked
Ah ふれちゃいそう でも イケナイの！
Ah, it feels like I'll touch you, but I shouldn't!
徐々に高なる鼓動と 止められないわ
My pulse races more and more, and I can't stop it
交わす言葉の記憶遠く 口元の動きに揺れ動く
Memories of our exchanged words fade, swaying with the movement of lips
濡れた髪を撫でた そして Ah
I stroked your wet hair, and then, Ah
そんないんじゃダメじゃない だって ココロの奥は
That's no good, because deep inside our hearts
違うんじゃない？ オレの青春
Aren't they different? My youth is not like that
そんなもんじゃない 熱く奥で果てたいよ
It's not so tame, I want to burn out passionately deep inside
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ オレは
Surely, if it's not you, I don't want it, I'm
イケナイ太陽
The forbidden sun
「赤い糸」なんて絵空事 でも下心でさえ信じたいの
A "red thread" is a pipe dream, but I want to believe even in my ulterior motives
オレは正しい キミも正しい
I'm right, you're right too
とにかくもう 左右されないぜ
Anyway, I won't be swayed anymore
騙し騙され胸うずく 下手な芝居が
Deceiving and being deceived, my heart aches; clumsy acting
より盛り上げる夜 息が耳に触れた 二人 Ah
Lifts the night even higher, our breath touching each other's ears, Ah
そんないんじゃダメじゃない だって ココロの奥は
That's no good, because deep inside our hearts
違うんじゃない？ あたしの青春
Aren't they different? My youth is not like that
そんなもんじゃない 熱く奥で果てたいよ
It's not so tame, I want to burn out passionately deep inside
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
Surely, if it's not you, I don't want it
あたし イケナイ太陽
I'm the forbidden sun
交わす言葉の記憶遠く 口元の動きに揺れ動く
Memories of our exchanged words fade, swaying with the movement of lips
濡れた髪を撫でた そして Ah
I stroked your wet hair, and then, Ah
ABC 続きかない そんないんじゃダメじゃない
Not continuing on from ABC, that's no good
だって ココロの奥は 違うんじゃない？
Because deep inside our hearts, aren't they different?
オレの青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth is not like that
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to burn out passionately deep inside
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
Surely, if it's not you, I don't want it
オレは イケナイ太陽
I'm the forbidden sun
絡み合う糸は 君と俺を結ぶ赤い糸
The intertwined threads are the red thread connecting you and me
いや、この曲番長のセクシーが溢れてていいですね。
Man, Banchou's sexiness really overflows in this song, it's great.
ちょっとね、父父になりましたね。父父だよ。
It became very "dad-like". Total dad energy.
いやっつ、あと社長の動きも激アツでしたね。
Also, Shachou's movements were super intense.
いやマジで、お立ち台で踊ったんだから。お立ち台で踊った。
Seriously, I danced on the pedestal! I danced on the pedestal.
お立ち台で踊り交いってね。いや、すごかった。
Dancing and interacting on the pedestal... man, it was amazing.
急にあの、平成ですね、さっきからちょっと。
Suddenly getting all Heisei-era vibe since a moment ago.
あの、平成というか何というか、ちょう、ちょうどね出たばっかだからね、
Well, Heisei era or whatever, it literally just came out recently, so...
デイ・ワン分かっちゃってきたな。いや、そういう感じのね。
We're starting to get the day-one vibe. Yeah, that kind of feel.
次の曲も続きますよということで。
And so, the next song continues as well!
かなでとらでの番なんじゃないの？
Isn't it Kanade and Torade's turn?
え？
Eh?
いいじゃん
That's fine.
ちょっとこう、結構ね、ヒートアップしちゃったから
I mean, we got pretty hyped up, so...
一旦クールダウンしようかね。
Let's cool down for a bit.
そうそうそう！
That's right, that's right!
いや、ラデの体力も持ちませんから
I mean, Raden's stamina won't hold up!
ちょっとゆっくりした曲をね、いこうね、はい。
So let's go with a relaxing song, okay. Yes.
じゃあ二人とも準備して下さいね。
Well then, both of you please get ready.
はい！
Okay!
はーい、はーい、ちょっと。
Okay, okay, hold on.
準備できた？はい！はい！
Are you ready? Yes! Yes!
それじゃあ、うたう？
Well then, shall we sing?
いや、立つ！あっ、立てるかな？立てる、立てた！
No, stand! Ah, can we stand? Standing, stood!
立って、ここまで踊ってきた。
Standing up, we danced all the way here.
では音楽をお願いします。
Now then, please start the music.
ちょっとダメよ、どうだった？
Wait, no, how was it?
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく 子どもの声
The moonlit night shows its face, and children's voices disappear
遠く遠くこの空のどこかに 君はいるんだろう
Far, far away, somewhere in this sky, you must be there
夏の終わりに2人で抜け出した この公園で見つけた
At the end of summer, we slipped away together and found in this park
あの星座 何だか覚えてる？
Do you remember what constellation that was?
夏の終わりに2人で抜け出した この公園で見つけた
At the end of summer, we slipped away together and found in this park
あの星座 何だか覚えてる？
Do you remember what constellation that was?
会えなくても記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace our memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
and want to see that same happiness
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks burst open
行きたいよ 君のところへ 今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to go to where you are, I want to run there right now
まっ暗で 何も見えない
It's so dark I can't see a thing,
怖くても 大丈夫
but it's okay to be scared.
数えきれない星空が 今もずっとここにあるんだよ
The countless starry sky is still right here, even now.
泣かないよ 昔 君と見た きれいな空だったから
I won't cry, because it was a beautiful sky I once saw with you.
あの道まで響く 靴の音が耳に残る
The sound of your shoes echoing down that street still remains in my ears.
大きな自分の影を見つめて想うのでしょう
You must be gazing at your huge shadow and thinking of it.
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに せつない気持ちふくらんでく
Even though nothing should have changed, a painful feeling swells up.
どんなに想ったって 君はもういない
No matter how much I think of you, you are no longer here.
行きたいよ 君のそばに 小さくても 小さくても
I want to go and be by your side, even if small, even if small
1番に君が好きだよ 強くいられる
I love you more than anyone, it makes me strong.
願いを流れ星に そっと唱えてみたけれど
I tried whispering a wish to a shooting star, but...
泣かないよ 届くだろう きれいな空に
I won't cry, it will reach that beautiful sky.
会えなくても記憶をたどって 同じ幸せを見たいんだ
Even if we can't meet, I trace our memories and want to see that same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ 小さな手をにぎりしめて
I want to go to where you are, clutching your little hand.
泣かないよ それはそれは きれいな空だった
I won't cry, it was, it was such a beautiful sky.
願いを流れ星に
I made a wish on a shooting star,
そっと唱えてみたけれど
and tried softly whispering it...
泣きたいよ 届かない 想いをこの空に…
I want to cry, sending this unreachable feeling into the sky...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ハイタッチ！ハイタッチ！
High five! High five!
ごめん！
Sorry!
ちょっと悲しい感じになっちゃった
It got a bit sad...
いや、めちゃくちゃライブでした！
Man, that was totally a live performance!
よかったよかった
Good, good!
もうライブパフォーマンスよ、マジで！
That was a real live performance, seriously!
完成度高すぎだろ
The completion level is way too high!
次！次！
Next! Next!
北海道行きたい
I want to go to Hokkaido.
あの、体力がないですね
Well, we lack stamina.
体力かぁ
Stamina, huh...
じゃあ、二人で歌う？ 一緒に
Then, shall we sing together as a duo?
やんたー！やんたー！
Yay! Yay!
なんだろ？何歌う？
What is it? What should we sing?
あの曲いっちゃいますか
Shall we go with that song?
おっ、何？何？
Oh, what? What?
なんだと思う？ やっぱお星様がキラキラしたら、もう一回キラキラしたくない？
What do you think? If the stars sparkle, don't you want them to sparkle again?
プラネタリウムから外に出ちゃう？
Go outside the planetarium?
いいか！それ！
Good! That!
何の曲かな？
What song could it be?
じゃあ行きましょう！ お願いしまーす！
Then let's go! Please!
午前二時 フミキリに 望遠鏡を担いでった
At 2:00 am, I carried a telescope to the crossing.
ベルトに結んだラジオ 雨は降らないらしい
The radio tied to my belt, it seems it won't rain.
二分後に君が来た 大袈裟な荷物しょって来た
Two minutes later you came, carrying exaggerated luggage.
始めようか 天体観測 ほうき星を探して
Let's begin, astronomical observation, searching for a broom star.
深い闇に飲まれないように 精一杯だった
I was doing my best not to be swallowed by the deep darkness.
君の震える手を 握ろうとしたあの日は 見えないモノを見ようとして
The day I tried to hold your trembling hand, trying to see the invisible...
望遠鏡を覗き込んだ 静寂を切り裂いて
I looked into the telescope, cutting through the silence.
いくつも声が生まれたよ
Many voices were born.
明日が僕らを呼んだって 返事もろくにしなかった
Even if tomorrow called us, I didn't reply properly.
「イマ」というほうき星 君と二人追いかけていた
Chasing the broom star called "Now" together with you.
気が付けばいつだって ひたすら何か探している
If I notice, I'm always searching for something.
幸せの定義とか 哀しみの置き場とか
Like the definition of happiness, or where to put sorrow.
生まれたら死ぬまで ずっと探してる
Since I was born until I die, I'm always searching.
さぁ 始めようか 天体観測 ほうき星を探して
Come on, let's begin, astronomical observation, searching for a broom star.
今まで見つけたモノは 全部覚えている
I remember everything I've found so far.
君の震える手を 握れなかった痛みも
Including the pain of not being able to hold your trembling hand.
知らないモノを知ろうとして 望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
I looked into the telescope, trying to know the unknown.
暗闇を照らす様な 微かな光 探したよ
Searching for a faint light that seems to illuminate the darkness.
そうして知った痛みを 未だに僕は覚えている
I still remember the pain I knew then.
「イマ」というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
I'm still chasing the broom star called "Now" alone.
背が伸びるにつれて 伝えたたい事も増えてった
As I grew taller, the things I wanted to tell increased.
宛名の無い手紙も 崩れる程重たかった
Unaddressed letters also piled up to the point of collapse.
僕は元気でいるよ 心配事も少ないよ ただひとつ 今も思い出すよ
I am doing well, with few worries, but there is one thing I still remember.
予報外れの雨に 打たれて 泣きだしそうな
Caught in unexpected rain, looking like you were about to cry.
君の震える手を 握れなかったあの日を
The day I couldn't hold your trembling hand.
見えてるモノを見落として 望遠鏡をまた担いで
Overlooking what I can see, I carried the telescope again.
静寂と暗闇の 帰り道を駆け抜けたら
And ran through the way home of silence and darkness.
そうして知った痛みが
And the pain I knew then
未だに僕を支えている
still supports me.
「イマ」というほうき星
The comet called "now"
今も一人追いかけている
I'm still chasing all by myself.
もう一度君に会おうとして
Wanting to meet you once more,
望遠鏡をまた担いで
I pick up the telescope again,
前と同じ午前二時
At two a.m., just like before,
フミキリまで駆けてくよ
I run to the railway crossing.
始めようか 天体観測
Shall we start our astronomical observation?
二分後に君が来なくとも
Even if you don't come two minutes later,
「イマ」というほうき星
The comet called "now"
君と二人追いかけている
I'm chasing with you, the two of us.
なんで爆弾発言なんだろ
Why is that a bombshell statement?
踊ってたっていうかパフォーマンス
Dancing, or rather, performing—
ほら、さっきからね、ぽかぽか探しに行ってたんだよ。
Look, we've been out looking for a warm spot for a while now.
めっちゃ歩き回っちゃった。歩き回ってたね。
We walked around so much. We really did walk around.
全員、ちょっとヘトヘト。そうだね。
Everyone's pretty exhausted. Yeah, exactly.
第1曲目からもうヘトヘトですけども。
Though we're already exhausted from the very first song.
でもね、このままちょっとラデンと番長の二人の期待の…なんて思ってるんですけれども。
But you know, we were thinking about Raden and Banchou's expectations...
じゃなくて、チャリで駆け上がりますか！
Instead of that, shall we race up on bikes?!
チャリで！行きましょう！
On bikes! Let's go!
じゃあ、音楽お願いします！
Then, music please!
駐車場のネコはアクビをしながら
The cat at the parking lot is yawning,
今日も一日を過ごしてゆく
spending another day today.
何も変わらない 穏やかな街並み
In a town where nothing changes, in the gentle cityscape,
みんな夏が来だって浮かれ気分なのに
everyone is excited saying that summer has come,
君は一人さえない顔してるネ
but you have such a sad expression on your face.
そうだ君に見せたいものがあるんだ
Yes, I have something I want to show you,
大きな五時半の夕やけ
the big sunset at 5:30.
子供の頃と同じように
Just like in our childhood days,
海も空も雲も僕等でさえも
paints the sea, the sky, the clouds, and even us
染めていくから…
as it paints it all over...
この長い長い下り坂を
I put you on the back of my bicycle
君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
on this long, long downhill slope,
ブレーキいっぱい握りしめて
I squeeze the brakes tight
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
and we go down slowly, slowly.
風鈴の音でウトウトしながら
While dozing off to the sound of wind chimes,
夢見ごこちでヨダレをたらしてる
dreaming, drooling a little.
いつもと同じ網戸越しの風の匂い
The same smell of the breeze through the screen door as always,
休日でみんなもゴロゴロしてるのに
everyone is lazing around on their day off,
君はずいぶん忙しい顔をしてるネ
but you have such a busy expression on your face.
そうだいつかのあの場所へ行こう
Yes, let's go to that place we went to sometime.
真夏の夜の波の音は
The sound of the waves on a midsummer night
不思議な程心静かになる
makes the heart so calm.
少しだけ全て忘れて
Forgetting everything for just a little while,
波の音の中包まれていく
wrapped in the sound of the waves.
この細い細い裏道を抜けて
Passing through this narrow, narrow back alley,
誰もいない大きな夜の海見ながら
while looking at the empty, big night sea,
線香花火に二人で
we set fire to the sparklers together,
ゆっくりゆっくり火をつける
slowly, slowly.
いつか君の涙がこぼれおちそうになったら
If one day your tears seem about to fall,
何もしてあげられないけど
I can't do anything, but
少しでもそばにいるよ…
I'll be by your side, even just a little...
この長い長い下り坂を
I put you on the back of my bicycle
君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
on this long, long downhill slope,
ブレーキいっぱい握りしめて
I squeeze the brakes tight
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
and we go down slowly, slowly.
Going down slowly, slowly,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
going down slowly, slowly.
めっちゃあったかい！
It's so warm!
夏だね！
It's summer!
夏が始まっちゃった！
Summer has started!
ああー！
Ahh!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
生歌最高！
Live singing is the best!
じゃあちょっと連続なんですけど
Well, it's continuous again, but...
よし、じゃあ最後4人で歌いたいと思います！
Alright, so finally the four of us want to sing!
おー！やったー！
Oh! Yay!
何歌うんですか？
What are you going to sing?
何歌うんだろうねえ！
I wonder what we're singing!
じゃあ皆さん聞いてください、お願いします！
Everyone, please listen, thank you!
せーの！ウィアー！
Ready, set! We are!
ウィアー！
We are!
羅針盤なんて 渋滞のもと 熱にうかされ 舵をとるのさ
The compass will only slow us down, filled with excitement, I take the helm
ホコリかぶってた 宝の地図も 確かめたのなら 伝説じゃない！
Even the dusty old treasure map won't be a legend anymore if we check it!
個人的な嵐は 誰かの バイオリズム乗っかって 思い過ごせばいい！
Personal storms can just be brushed off by riding someone else's biorhythm!
ありったけの夢をかき集め 捜し物を探しに行くのさ
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams, we're going to search for everything we're looking for
ONE PIECE
探し物を探しに行くのさ
We're going to search for everything we're looking for
ONE PIECE
羅針盤なんて 渋滞のもと
The compass will only slow us down,
熱にうかされ 舵をとるのさ
filled with excitement, I take the helm
ホコリかぶってた 宝の地図も
Even the dusty old treasure map
確かめたのなら 伝説じゃない！
won't be a legend anymore if we check it!
個人的な嵐は 誰かの バイオリズム乗っかって
Personal storms can just be brushed off by riding someone else's biorhythm!
思い過ごせばいい！ ありったけの夢をかき集め
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams,
ありったけの夢をかき集め 捜し物を探しに行くのさ
We're going to search for everything we're looking for
ポケットのコイン それと You wanna be my Friend?
A coin in the pocket, and You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ぜんぶまに受けて 信じちゃっても 肩を押されて 1歩リードさ
Even though I believe everything they tell me, if you push me on the shoulder, I'll be one step ahead
ぜんぶまに受けて 信じちゃっても
Even though I believe everything they tell me,
肩を押されて 1歩リードさ
if you push me on the shoulder, I'll be one step ahead
今度会えたなら 話すつもりさ
If we ever meet again, I'll tell you all about it
それからのことと これからのこと
What I've been doing and where I'm headed next
つまりいつも ピンチは 誰かに アピール出来る いいチャンス
In other words, being in a pinch is always a good opportunity to ask for backup
自意識過剰に！
and overcome one's excessive shyness!
しみたれた夜を ぶっとばせ！
Full steam ahead through the stingy night!
宝箱に キョウミはないけど
I'm not interested in treasure anyway
ポケットに ロマン それと You wanna be my Friend?
A romance in my pocket, and You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ありったけの夢をかき集め 捜し物を探しに行くのさ
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams, we're going to search for everything we're looking for
We're going to search for everything we're looking for
ポケットのコイン それと You wanna be my Friend?
A coin in the pocket, and You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We are!
ウィアー！ウィアー！ウィアー！
We are! We are! We are!
いやー！やばい、もう時間だ、時間だ！
Man! Oh no, it's already time, it's time!
最後に、お知らせがあります！
Lastly, we have an announcement!
えー、改めてになりますが、えー明日0時、つまり今日の24時に『Midsummer Citrus』がデジタルリリースされます！
Um, once again, tomorrow at 0:00, which is today at 24:00, 'Midsummer Citrus' will be digitally released!
えー、こちら、YouTube君でも聴けるようになります！
Um, you'll be able to listen to it on YouTube as well!
そして、えー来月の配信なんですが、いつも10日にReGLOSSのこの配信やってるんですけれども
And, um, for next month's broadcast, we usually do this ReGLOSS broadcast on the 10th, but...
えー8月は8月1日に配信予定となっておりますので、間違えないように注意してください！
Um, August's is scheduled for August 1st, so please be careful not to make a mistake!
8月1日、1日だよ！よろしかね？よろしくお願いしまーす！
August 1st, the 1st! Got it? Thank you very much!
いや、楽しかったね、カラオケ！いやカラオケとは思えない
Man, karaoke was so fun! Well, doesn't even feel like karaoke.
今日も重いだけどね
It's heavy today too, though.
全力でしゃ…おいしいもの食べた
We went all out ta... ate delicious food.
そうだね
That's right.
みんなも楽しんでくれたかな
I hope everyone enjoyed it too.
よかった！
Awesome!
たくさんのね、あのアンケートをご回答ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to everyone who filled out the survey!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、じゃあ今日はこんなとこでもありますか
Well then, shall we wrap it up around here for today?
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
それではまた来月お会いしましょう！
Well then, see you next month!
見てくれてありがとね！バイバイ！
Thanks for watching! Bye-bye!
バイバイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
新曲初披露もあるよ♪ 真夏のReGLOSSカラオケ
Featuring a new song debut! Midsummer ReGLOSS Karaoke